# **Shoaib Ahmed**

■ <u>ahmed.shoaib1729@gmail.com</u> □ +8801686454469 ■ <u>Shoaib Ahmed</u> <u>■edge555.github.io</u>

Google Scholar Profile - Shoaib Ahmed

#### Summary

I'm passionate about using my skills in Computer Vision, NLP, and Generative AI to tackle complex cognitive challenges and create technologies that genuinely benefit people. With 2.5 years of strong software development experience, I'm eager to explore new frontiers in these fields and build solutions that make a real impact.

#### **Research & Publications**

## **Invariant Scattering Transform for Medical Imaging**

https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.04771

- Applied wavelet technique for medical image classification
- Used scattering transform to build signal representation for image classification

## **Areas of Research Interest**

➤ Computer Vision ➤ Generative AI

 $\triangleright$  LLM

➤ Virtual Reality

#### Education

### **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering**

November 2017 - April 2022

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology • CGPA 3.081 out of 4.00

Dhaka, Bangladesh

· Achieved highest marks in Data Structure, Algorithms, Database, and Software Development Labs

## **Undergraduate Thesis**

## Reportbyte: An Advanced Business Analytics System

An advanced business analytic and assistant system that provides four kinds of services (Chatbot, Question-answering bot, Data visualization tool, and Predictive data analysis tool) built with machine learning and artificial intelligence tools. **Advisor**: Mohammad Moinul Hoque, Associate Professor, Department of CSE, AUST

## **Experiences**

**Software Engineer** (2 years 6 Months)

Cefalo (mail@cefalo.com)

September 2022 - Present

Dhaka, Bangladesh

## Key Responsibilities:

- Integrating AI support to the project
- Actively fixed critical production bugs of overseas customers
- Implement features for a large data migration system that can process 1 billion data
- Did R&D on some complex features that improved the client's business

#### **Software Engineer** (3 Months)

Enosis Solutions Ltd. (info@enosisbd.com)

June 2022 - August 2022 Dhaka, Bangladesh

#### Key Responsibilities:

- Improved performance of Machinery Design Software with complex mathematical calculation
- Refactored some legacy code to much better maintainable code
- Made changes in an automated testing system that shortens the testing time by 15%

# Educator (1 year 11 Months)

January 2023 - Present

Amar iSchool

Dhaka, Bangladesh

#### System Design Course: Zero to Intermediate

Course Curriculum

- Computer Architecture, System Performance Metrics, Scalability, Networking Basics
- Cache, Database, REST API, Message Queue

#### **Trainer of Competitive Programming (2 years)**

January 2020 - January 2022

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Taught algorithms and data structures to 300+ students in my university's CSE department.
- Mentored the students to learn about different online judges and solve programming problems.

## **Achievements and Participations**

- Participated in more than 10 national programming contests achieving best rank of 4th place
- Solved almost 4000 Programming across all top-tier online judges
- Attended 300+ online contests among global participants
- Achieved **Expert** rank at Codeforcecs
- Got invited to take Google Foobar Challenge, Cleared 4 out of 5 rounds

## **Standardized Test Scores**

**IELTS** (International English Language Testing System)

Overall Score: Band 7 (Listening: 7.5, Reading: 7.5, Writing: 6, Speaking: 6.5)

## Certifications

## Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

- · Learnt to clean and organize data for analysis using spreadsheets, SQL, and R programming
- Visualize and present data findings in dashboards, presentations, and commonly used visualization platforms

#### **Involvements**

## **Microsoft Learn Student Ambassadors**

December 2019 - March 2022

Beta Ambassador

- Conducted workshop on competitive programming
- Reached global audience for programming content

## **AUST Programming and Informatics Club**

December 2021 - January 2023

Joint Secretary

- Formed the club to increase programming activity
- Organized National Inter-University Programming Contest of 400 participants

#### **Skills**

Programming: Python, C++, C#, SQL

ML Libraries: Sci-Kit Learn, Numpy, Pandas, Scipy

**DL Libraries:** TensorFlow, PyTorch, Keras

IDE: Jupyter, Google Colab, Visual Studio Code

#### References

#### Dr. Mohammad Shafiul Alam (shafiul.cse@aust.edu)

Professor

Department of Computer Science and Engineering

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology, Bangladesh

#### Faisal Muhammad Shah (faisal.cse@aust.edu)

Associate Professor

Department of Computer Science and Engineering

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology, Bangladesh

# Md. Moinul Hoque (moinul@aust.edu)

Associate Professor

Department of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE)

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology, Bangladesh